kylottery.com 2018-06-04

# Kentucky Lottery

**KENTUCKY LOTTERY CORPORATION**

**PRIVACY POLICY AND LEGAL DISCLAIMERS**

Effective: July 24, 2017

Version 3

Thank you for visiting kylottery.com, the official player website of the Kentucky Lottery Corporation.

**Use of This Website and Acceptance of Policy**

Your access and use of the Kentucky Lottery Corporation (“Kentucky Lottery”) website is subject to the terms of this policy as set out below and all applicable laws. By accessing and using this site, you accept these terms without limitation or qualification. **If you do not agree to the terms of this policy, then do not access this website.   **

**Definitions**

As used herein, “this policy” refers to this Privacy Policy and Legal Disclaimers; “this website” refers to, collectively, the Kentucky Lottery’s website kylottery.com, mobile application or mobile app, and mobile site ; “Fun Club” or “Fun Club Rewards” refers to the information and services available through this website; “online” refers to use of the internet or any other means to access this website and the website of any of the Kentucky Lottery’s contractors, subcontractors, or third parties involved in producing or delivering this website  or services; “iLottery,” “online play,” or “play online” refers to the purchase of lottery tickets through this website and is not the purchase of lottery tickets at a retail location; “this service” refers to all services, functions, and features described in this policy; “account” refers to a Kentucky Lottery Fun Club account registered on this website, which includes, for eligible players, the use of the account to purchase lottery tickets using this website; “we,” “us,” and “our” refer to the Kentucky Lottery, its agents, contractors, sub-contractors, and third parties involved in producing or delivering this website or services; and “you” or “your” refers to you, the user.  

**Acceptance of Additional Terms**

By using this website, you represent that you understand and agree to this policy. Your use of this website also constitutes your agreement to the Fun Club Terms of Use, and if you use your account to purchase lottery tickets through this website, your agreement to the iLottery Terms of Use (both of which are posted on this website), and all game rules, statutes, regulations, policies and directives of the Kentucky Lottery and the Commonwealth of Kentucky, all of which are incorporated by reference.

**Changes to Policy**

We may change this policy, the Fun Club Terms of Use, the iLottery Terms of Use, game rules, or any other documents applicable to your use of this site, at any time, with or without notice.  All changes are effective upon posting.  Your continued use of this website after changes are posted constitutes your acceptance of those changes.

**Information Collected Automatically**

Some of your information is automatically collected when you visit and use this website.  The server on which the website is located collects and saves only the default information customarily logged by web server software which may include, but is not limited to, the date and time of your visit; the originating IP address; the pages and images requested; information about how you linked to this website; searches you initiated; items you clicked on; the geographical location of your IP address; pages you visited; your mobile device identifier and hardware; your network carrier and the type of browser and operating system you used.  This information is used to improve this website by making it more useful and accessible to visitors.  This information is not considered to be personally identifiable information (PII). 

**Information Voluntarily Submitted**

We may, depending on the services you request, collect additional information you voluntarily provide, including, but not limited to, your name, address, telephone number, email address, date of birth, all or the last four digits of your social security number, credit and/or debit card number, bank account number, routing number(s), transaction history, username, password, IP address, player identification number, and geographical location. This information may be used to provide your requested transaction or service, verify your eligibility for a requested transaction or service, contact you regarding a requested transaction or service, record transactions, improve the website, enforce terms and conditions, protect our rights and property, and otherwise perform the purpose for which the information was provided. If you do not provide all or any part of the personal information requested, your attempt to register for an account, update your account, or access or use your account, may not be processed. We require certain personal information to comply with the Internal Revenue Code and state and federal income reporting requirements and tax withholding requirements.  **When you submit information to us, you are authorizing us (and all third parties authorized by us) to use, transmit, disclose and store such information for all purposes necessary to provide the information, activities, and services offered in connection with this website.   If you do not want your personal information collected, please do not submit it to us.**

**Use and Disclosure of Information**

We reserve all rights necessary to use and disclose your l information, including personal information, as required and/or permitted pursuant to all laws, rules and regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the Kentucky Lottery or its products.  Any information which you submit to us, or which is collected by us, via this website, including your name and other information, may be subject to disclosure under the Kentucky Open Records Act, KRS 61.870, et seq. or as otherwise required by state or federal law and in response to subpoenas, court orders or other legal process.  Subject to applicable legal restrictions, we may disclose your information to entities that perform marketing services on our behalf or with other entities with which we may have joint marketing agreements. We may disclose your information if it is necessary in connection with other business services including, but not limited to, administration of this website, customer services or convenience, service quality, business management and operation, risk assessment, security, fraud and crime prevention/detection, monitoring, research and analysis, marketing, customer purchasing preferences and trends, dispute resolution, credit checking and debt collection, account maintenance and fulfillment activities, and awarding and payment of prizes.

We may employ tools provided by third parties such as Hotjar and Google Analytics to support Display Advertising, including Remarketing, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, data collection via advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers, the DoubleClick Campaign Manager integration and/or Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. In general, this means that third-party vendors, including Google, may show Kentucky Lottery ads on sites across the Internet based upon visits to this website. To implement these tools, Kentucky Lottery and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies and third- party cookies together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on past visits to this website. The Google Analytics Privacy Policy is available at <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.  To opt-out of the Google Analytic Advertising Features, please go to <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.  You can also generally opt-out of receiving personalized ads from third party advertisers and ad networks who are members of the [Network Advertising Initiative (NAI)](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) or who follow the [Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) by visiting the opt-out pages on the NAI site and DAA site.

**Winner Information**

Except where prohibited by law or policy, if you win a prize, you understand and agree that we may use your name, city, prize amount, and any photograph, video or audio recording, in any medium, for promotional, advertising, and/or publicity purposes. You understand and agree that we may freely use, reproduce, and display this information, in whole or in part, alone or together with other information, through any and all forms of media, in any manner, anywhere, in perpetuity, and without restriction, reservation, or limitation.

## 

**Age and Identification Information**

To successfully register for a Fun Club account, or successfully update your existing account, you must: be at least 18 years of age; have your age and identity verified; have a valid U.S. address and be in compliance with federal, state, and local laws, the Fun Club Terms of Use and all Kentucky Lottery directives, rules and regulations.  In order to use your account to purchase lottery tickets on line, you must have a valid Kentucky address; be physically located in Kentucky at the time of purchase; have sufficient funds in your account to make the purchase; and be in compliance with federal, state, and local laws, the iLottery Terms of Use, and all Kentucky Lottery directives, rules and regulations.

By submitting the information necessary to register to be a member of Fun Club and to have an account, to update your existing account, and use your account, you consent to our use of any age verification and identity verification technology or method we deem appropriate.

We do not guarantee that our age verification and identity verification technology and methods will be able to locate records for and verify every person. You will not be able to use your Fun Club account if your age and identity cannot be verified. If you cannot successfully register for an account or update your existing account, we may nevertheless retain the profile information you submitted for an indefinite period of time.

**Use of this Website by Children is Prohibited**

Use of this website, including all of its content and services, by anyone under 18 years of age is strictly prohibited.  We do not knowingly collect personal information from or create account profiles of persons under the age of 18.  Consistent with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, we will not knowingly collect any information from children. While our account registration process uses age and identity verification software, users are cautioned, however, that information collected automatically or voluntarily submitted in certain ways, such as email or survey, will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult.

**Location Information**

You must be physically located within the Commonwealth of Kentucky to purchase a lottery ticket using the website, including the mobile app.  We use a variety of geo-location technology and methods to verify your location. By registering for or updating your existing account, and using an account or this service, you consent to have your location verified by our standard geo-location check. Our standard location check is automatically activated any time you attempt to make a purchase. Your location will not be checked after you leave this website.

If eligible, you may purchase lottery tickets through the website by using your mobile device.  You may connect to the Internet using a WIFI connection or through your mobile service provider using your data plan. Connecting to the Internet through your mobile provider requires registration of your device by using the mobile geo-location opt-in function on the website. We cannot guarantee that mobile geo-location opt-in will be available through your provider, that you will be able to opt-in, or that geo-location technology will be able to verify that you are located within the state. 

We do not guarantee that our geo-location technology will verify the location of every person physically located within Kentucky. If we are unable to verify that you are physically located within Kentucky, your access will be blocked and you are prohibited from purchasing any lottery ticket through this website.

Information relating to your location and/or the location of your mobile device will only be used by us and our staff and will not be shared with or sold to third parties. We do, however, reserve the right to disclose this information at any time in accordance with any law, regulation, or request from a court or government agency, to avoid liability or protect our rights or property. A record confirming your location may be retained for a specific period of time according to retention policy.

**Cookies**

This website uses “cookies” to customize your browsing experience.  Cookies are text files stored on your web browser to provide a means of distinguishing you from other visitors to the website. To better serve you, the website uses “transactional cookies” to enhance or customize your visit to the website and to recognize you when you visit again.  The software or hardware you use to access the website may allow you to refuse new cookies or delete existing cookies.  However, if you refuse or delete these cookies, this may limit your ability to take advantage of some features of this website.

**Personalized Advertising**

KLC uses personalized advertising to display ads to you based on information gathered when you visit and interact with our website or services.  We may use third-party ad-serving companies, cookies and other technologies to enable advertisers to learn about ads you see and click and your visits to our website.  These technologies help to provide you with more relevant advertising.  Personal information that we collect from you is not linked to the information collected for purposes of displaying personalized advertising. 

**Retention of Information**

We retain information collected through this website in accordance with applicable record retention policies, disposal schedules, and state law.  Where no retention policy, disposal schedule or state law applies, we may retain information for any period of time or not at all.

**Email Marketing Communications**

If you register for an account, update your existing account, or otherwise provide personal information through this website, you may receive email messages from us, including marketing messages regarding our products, such as games and promotions, from the Kentucky Lottery, IGT Corporation or any of the Kentucky Lottery’s other contractors, subcontractors, or third parties involved in producing or delivering this website or services (on behalf of the Kentucky Lottery).  You have the right to ask in writing not to receive direct marketing material from us.  If applicable, you can amend your previous preferences by following the “unsubscribe” instructions at the bottom of our email(s) to you.    Please allow us a reasonable period of time to satisfy your request.  This will not apply to email messages concerning your Fun Club Membership or account.  

**Text Message Communications**

To receive text messages about our games and promotions, you must opt-in by checking the box authorizing us to send you such text messages.

**Disclaimer Regarding Links to other Websites**

Links to other organizations on this website are provided for informational purposes only.  In providing these links, we do not endorse the content, products, services, viewpoints, or security of these other websites.  This policy does not apply to other websites.  If you leave this website through a link, this Privacy Policy no longer applies and you are subject to the terms and policies of that website.

**Security**

Security measures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of this website as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.  We do not, however, guarantee security in any way.  Your use of this website is at your own risk and we are not liable for any damages or losses resulting from a security breach except as required by law.

**Disclaimer**

While the Kentucky Lottery uses reasonable efforts to include accurate and up to date information on this website, errors or omissions may occur. We make no warranties or representations as to the accuracy of the information provided on this website. The information provided on this website is provided “as is” and without warranties of any kind, either expressed or implied, including, but not limited to, implied warranties of merchant ability and fitness for a particular purpose. We do not warrant that the functions necessary to access the information provided on this website will be uninterrupted or error-free, that defects will be corrected, or that this website or the server that makes it available are free of viruses or other harmful components. We do not warrant or guarantee continuous, uninterrupted or secure access to this website. Under no circumstances, including, but not limited to, negligence by act or omission, shall the Kentucky Lottery be liable for any direct, incidental, consequential, indirect or punitive damages that result from the use of, or the inability to use, the information provided on this website. The information provided in this policy should not be construed as business, legal or other advice.

**Restrictions on Use of Website Materials**

The Kentucky Lottery maintains this website to provide information and communication. You may download material displayed on this site for non-commercial personal use only, provided that you also retain all copyright and other proprietary notices contained on the materials. You may not, however, distribute, modify, transmit, reuse, repost or use the contents of this site for public or commercial purposes, including the text, images, audio and video.

**Governing Law**

This Privacy Policy shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. 

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this website or the Privacy Policy, please contact our Customer Service by email at: [help@kylottery.com](mailto:help@kylottery.com) or call 877-789-4532.

Effective July 24, 2017

Version 3
